Abdulwahab O. Jimoh

Frontend Developer | React | Nextjs | Typescript

omoniyi.success@gmail.com

-+234(704) 367-8597 / +234(818)802-6726

in linkedin.com/in/wabjay

https://abdulwahab.vercel.app

I'm a front-end developer, I have prioritized refining customer satisfaction in approaches to a host of projects I have overseen which has in turn endeared me to clients. Having devoted my time to science and technology, I recognize the quest of man to use the web as a tool for immense possibilities and I am keen to help actualize the vision.

I surely realize the need for continuous updates, as it is the only constant in the field of technology to provide the best website development experience to my customers.

Skills

Problem Solving • Written Communication • Redux.js

Front-End Development • JavaScript Frameworks • Tailwind CSS

React.js • NextJs • Typescript • JavaScript • Redux Toolkits

Experience

Pixelgum

Frontend Developer

May 2021 - Present || Part-time

Shaping the future of commerce and entrepreneurship – building and advocating for inclusive and thoughtful experiences for over three million merchants across the globe.

- Converted the figma designs to pixel perfect implemented code with full responsiveness using plain HTML, CSS and JavaScript and JavaScript frameworks.
- Collaborate with the design team and the backend developers to create user oriented web applications.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Nextjs, Typescript, TailwindCss, Sass, Bootstrap,

Ethco Group Limited

Frontend Developer

Aug 2022 - May 2023 || Part-time

Building the landing pages, admin web app for helping Ethnic and Independent convenience store owners.

- Converted the Ethco figma landing page to pixel perfect implemented code with full responsiveness using plain HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Worked on Airtable API to receive data from forms.
- Worked on the Ethco admin portal using next.js and ant design forms.
- Used redux for the state management and consumed the API created from the backend.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Nextjs, React-redux, Airtable, AntDesign, Formspree

Ayrem

Frontend Web Developer

May 2020 - Dec 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Ayrem is a safe and trustworthy way for Africans to purchase crypto, gift card and data plans conveniently at unbeatable rates.

- Convert the Ayrem figma landing page to pixel perfect implemented code with full responsiveness.
- Worked on the Ayrem web app design of over 50 pages and converted it using plain HTML,
 CSS and JavaScript code.
- Consumed the API created backend and implemented it on the Ayrem web app.
- Designed and implemented the Ayrem admin backend office using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Strategize with the team to implement features to make the website more engaging to the users.
- Built a flexible and functional user and admin dashboard within the specified time of production and was able to get at least 5k+ users in the first month after launch.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Axios

Projects

Comfytag || Web App

<u>User website</u> <u>Admin Dashboard</u>

An online ticket platform for events and activities. Provide a convenient and secure way for you to purchase tickets to your favorite music festivals, sporting events, theatrical performances, and more. Development of the Backend system and the Admin dashboard and also the user website.

- Built the backend system with Nodejs and ExpressJs, MongoDB for the database management and deployed on Heroku.
- Developed the admin dashboard with Nextjs, React redux for the data management, AntDesign for the design system.
- Developed the user website with React Vite, contextApi, AntDesign and Axios.

Technologies used: ExpressJs, Vite, ReactJs, NextJs, Redux toolkit, axios, AntDesign.

Maxim | Landing page

Maxim Landing page

Maxim Infrastructure connects and processes financial and non-financial data sources into usable data formats available for individual credit and background appraisals globally.

 Designed the landing page with Html, TailwindCss, JavaScript and implemented form designs to email integration with Airtable.

Technologies used: TailwindCss, JavaScript, CSS, Airtable.

Ownerfi | Web App Development

Ownerfi Web app

Ownerfi is an innovative real estate company that provides homeowners and landlords a creative way to sell their property and at the same time earn true passive income without the stress of Property management. Our creative owner financing solution is a groundbreaking product for millions of American landlords and homeowners.

Developed project with reactjs, built a step form and manage data state with context api.
 Implement ReactQuill for rich text editor and address autocomplete using google place autocomplete. Used firebase for database stage and user authentication.

Technologies used: Reactis, Context API, ReactQuill, Firebase, Google place API

Techtank Labs | Website Developer

Techtank web app

TechTanks is an IT solutions (Web, mobile app, custom software development, type approval, etc) company in Nigeria. We are a diverse group of digital strategists, technologists, critical thinkers, and thought leaders. We offer a comprehensive set of software development and technical services from requirements discovery to support and promote high quality and continuous improvement.

• Designed the landing pages with reactjs and implemented form designs to email integration with EmailJs.

Technologies used: Reactjs, EmailJs, Bootstrap, CSS

Education

Kwara state polytechnic

National Diploma, Computer Science 2012 - 2014

Licenses & Certifications

- National Diploma Kwara State Polytechnic
- Jobberman Soft-skills Training Jobberman Nigeria
- Fundamental of Digital Marketing Google